No wonder the Ruins of the King's Tomb were impregnable.
难怪零落王墓至今无人能破
Who knew we'd run into something like this?
谁能料到居然有这种东西？
Denken,
邓肯
is that something you can deal with?
那个你也能对付得了吗？
There's one thing I can say for certain.
只有一点老朽敢说
If this weren't an exam, I would've already broken my bottle.
要不是这是考试 老朽早就摔碎瓶子了
ORIGINAL STORY BY KANEHITO YAMADA / TSUKASA ABE
（原作：山田钟人 作画：阿部司）
We call the lord of that dungeon Spiegel,
世人称迷宫的主人为“史毕哲”
the Water-Mirror Fiend.
意即“水镜恶魔”
It's a monster from mythical times that comes out
那是贤者埃维希英雄传说中
in Ewig the Sage's heroic tales.
神话时代的魔物
We believe that
人们认为
Spiegel reads the memories of those who enter the dungeon
水镜恶魔会读取进入迷宫者的记忆
and creates a clone of them.
并制造出这些人的复制体
There are modern-day monsters with
尽管这个时代也有
similar traits, like the Einsam.
拥有类似能力的魔物 比如幻影鬼
But the clones that Spiegel creates are tangible
但水镜恶魔的复制体拥有实体
and perfectly copy people's
并且能完美复制一个人的
abilities, mana, and even techniques.
能力、魔力甚至是实力
That is why the Ruins of the King's Tomb is still uncharted.
所以零落王墓才会至今无人能破
Why did Sense choose this dungeon as the exam location?
赞泽为什么选择 这处迷宫作为考试地点呢？
Fighting your clone means fighting an evenly-matched opponent.
复制体就是自身旗鼓相当的对手
Calm self-analysis and teamwork is necessary
必须要冷静下来 进行自我分析以及团队合作
in order to defeat the clones without any casualties.
才能击败这些复制体 且无人伤亡
This exam is very fitting for a pacifist like her.
这个考试还真是符合 她这个和平主义者的风格
This is bad…
情况不妙…
Let's retreat.
先撤再说！
Denken!
邓肯！
Well then…
那接下来…
What shall we do?
该怎么办？
A dead end, huh?
是死路吗？
I guess we're cornered.
看来无路可逃了
Four-eyes,
眼镜男
I want to hear your opinion, as an expert in cloning magic.
你是分身魔法的专家 我想听听你的意见
Do you mind?
可以吧？
As I've said before, my name is Land.
我说过了 我叫做兰托
Well, whatever…
算了 也不是什么大不了的事
How perfect of a copy is that clone of mine?
你认为那个复制体 把我复制得多完美？
Übel, you're the type
尤贝尔 你这个人啊
who is talkative even during a battle, aren't you?
是那种就算在战斗中 话也很多的人 对吧？
It's like you'd die if you stayed quiet.
叫你安静好像会死一样
Good observation.
观察力真好
Yeah, I might die.
是啊 可能会死喔
That thing is silent.
那个东西很安静呢
I guess it hasn't copied my memories or personality.
看来它并没有复制我的记忆或是个性
No, it probably just can't speak.
不是 它可能只是单纯不能说话罢了
During the first attack,
第一次攻击的时候
it pulled out the bottle
它拿走了我怀中
with the evacuation golem out of my pocket.
撤离用的哥列姆
I see.
这样啊
That is indeed something I would do.
我的话确实会这么做
It's also knowledgeable about us.
它对我们也有所了解
The reason why it's not attacking us even though we're cornered
即使我们已经无路可逃 它却没有攻过来
is because it's wary of your Sorganeil.
就是在警戒你的目光束缚魔法
Or it just enjoys watching people suffer.
不然就是在享受别人因它受苦的模样
That's not funny.
一点都不好笑
You're bleeding a lot.
你流了好多血
Four-eyes, you're not going to last very long at this rate.
眼镜男 再这样下去 你撑不了多久的
Yeah…
确实如此
Can I ask you one last thing?
最后能再问你一个问题吗？
Are you the real Four-eyes?
你是眼镜男的本体吗？
Who knows?
这个嘛
I wonder…
谁知道呢？
Use my bottle.
你就用我的瓶子吧
That is for your own survival.
那是你逃命用的东西
Interesting…
有意思…
I see.
这样啊
Well then, Four-eyes, wait here for a second.
那么眼镜男 你在这里等一下
I'll get your bottle back.
我去把你的瓶子夺回来
Hey, wait--
喂 等等…
Of course, it will come towards me.
果然直接朝我冲来
In order to use Sorganeil,
要使用目光束缚魔法的话
the target's entire body must be within view.
视线必须容纳目标全身
The first one to miscalculate the distance between us will lose.
算错距离的那一方就输定了
If our abilities are equal, winning and losing is up to luck.
如果实力相当的话 输赢就交给运气吧
Luck has never been on my side,
我打从以前运气就不好呢
so I hate fights that depend on luck.
所以我讨厌靠运气决胜负
That's why I have no interest in fighting myself.
正因如此 我一点也不想跟自己战斗
My goodness…
真是的
I'm just helplessly suicidal, aren't I?
我还真是无可救药地急着送死啊
As usual, I'm unlucky.
果然这次也不走运
This is why I hate these things…
所以我才讨厌这样
But
不过…
it seems you were even more unlucky than me.
看来你比我还要倒霉呢
Four-eyes, that was surprisingly fast.
眼镜男 你来得还真快
As I thought, the bottle was fake too, huh?
如我所料 瓶子果然也是假的
Übel,
尤贝尔
you knew that it was my clone who was fatally injured?
你早就知道 受了致命伤的是我的分身？
Why did you put your life in danger?
那你干嘛还急着去送死？
I guess it's because I was convinced that you'd come for me.
因为我相信你会来救我
Did I come across as such a nice guy?
我看起来像个好人吗？
No, not at all.
不 一点也不像
More like, that's not relevant at all.
不管怎么说 那种事怎么样都好
Four-eyes,
眼镜男
you didn't even try to accept my bottle.
你甚至都没想过要拿走我的瓶子
You don't want anyone to die because of you, am I right?
你并不希望有人因你而死吧？
That's why I created
所以我才创造出
a situation in which I would die because of you.
我可能会因你而死的情况
Thank you, Four-eyes.
谢谢你了 眼镜男
I feel like I got to know you a little better.
我感觉自己又多了解你一点了
Is that right? Good for you.
是这样吗？那还真是太好了
Do you feel like you can relate to me yet?
那你已经可以跟我产生共鸣了吗？
I'll probably need some more time.
应该还需要一点时间
I'm pretty sure we're near the innermost depths…
我们应该已经在最深处的房间附近了
Mistress Frieren, I see stairs over there.
芙莉莲大人 那边有楼梯
Fern, show me the map.
菲伦 地图借我看一下
I think we've explored every corner of this floor.
这一层每个地方都已经去过了
There's a hidden room behind this wall.
这道墙后面有一间暗室
I'm sure there are treasures.
我敢说里面一定有宝藏
Judging from this atmosphere, there's a possibility
照这个氛围来看 里面
that a rare grimoire is hidden in here.
可能是本很稀有的魔导书
But there was nothing that looked
可是并没有看起来
like an entrance anywhere.
像是入口的地方
True…
确实如此
But according to the layout,
但是从建筑构造来看
there definitely should be a room here.
这里一定有个房间的
Mistress Frieren, this is amazing!
芙莉莲大人 这真的好惊人！
It depicts the achievements of the king who was buried here.
墙上说的是 埋葬于此地的国王的丰功伟业
I have never seen a mural from the Unified Dynasty era in such
我还是第一次看到状态这么完好的
pristine condition.
统一王朝的壁画
This is a valuable find.
这真的是重大发现
It's magnificent.
确实是这样呢
This raid is almost going a little too smoothly.
这趟攻克之旅也有点太平顺了吧
We might just pass the exam before we know it.
说不定不知不觉就通过考试了
That might be.
确实有可能会这样呢
What's wrong? Why are you gathered here?
怎么回事？大家怎么都聚在这里？
Guessing from the layout,
从建筑构造来说
the innermost depths should be somewhere beyond this hall.
这道墙的后面 应该就是最深处的房间了
So?
然后呢？
It's been half a day since that thing stationed itself there.
那个东西已经在那里停留半天了
Things are starting to get fun.
事情开始变得有趣了
Now this is how dungeon raids are supposed be.
攻略迷宫就是应该要这样
A perfect clone, huh?
是完美的复制体呢
That thing seems to be just as strong as me.
那个东西看起来跟我一样强
Unless we do something about that clone,
不想点办法处理那个复制体的话
we can't make it to the innermost depth.
是无法抵达最深处的
Do you have any suggestions?
有什么建议吗？
Let's see…
让我想想
If that thing is a perfect replica of me,
如果那是完美复制我的复制体
its weakness would be the same as a real life mage.
弱点就应该跟魔法使本尊一样
To defeat a mage of a higher caliber,
要击败高阶魔法使
one would use a restraining spell or hypnosis magic.
一般都是使用拘禁魔法 或是精神操作魔法
I'm resistant to both, though.
不管哪个我都有抵御力就是了
But it might create a window of opportunity.
但应该能制造出破绽吧
You should be able to seize that opportunity and defeat it.
如果是你的话 应该能够把握这个机会打败复制体
Methode,
梅特蒂
you're skilled in those kinds of tricks.
你很擅长这种伎俩吧
I wouldn't call myself "skilled" but…
算不上是很擅长 不过…
Excuse me.
失礼了
How intriguing…
还真是有趣
My restraining spell won't work on you.
拘禁魔法对你起不了作用呢
You smell good.
好好闻喔
This should work on anyone unless
只要魔力相差不大
there's a significant difference in mana.
一般而言都应该要有效果的
Frieren,
芙莉莲小姐
please look into my eyes next.
接下来请看着我的眼睛
Hypnosis magic doesn't work either.
精神操作魔法也没有用呢
I am not able to break Frieren's mental defense.
我的话 连芙莉莲小姐的精神防御都破不了
Oh my…
哎呀…
I guess she really is resistant to both.
看来她真的对两者都有抵御力呢
But although her mental defense is complex and strong,
虽说她的精神防御术式 很复杂也很坚固
it seems to be a very old system.
但应该是很久以前的魔法了
An expert in hypnosis magic may be able to find its weakness.
如果是精神魔法方面的专家 也许可以找到其中的弱点
Can you think of anyone among the examinees?
你想得到的考生中有这样的人吗？
Edel, the second-class mage, may be able to.
二级魔法使的艾蒂露应该能办到
But unlike me, she has absolutely no combat skills,
但是她跟我不同 她完全没有战斗方面的技能
so I honestly don't know if she can make it this far.
说实话 她能不能 抵达这里都是个问题
And first of all,
而且在这之前
hypnosis magic doesn't have any effect unless the target has a mind.
精神操作魔法 对于没有心智的对象无法产生作用
Who knows
目前
if the clones are replicated to that extent.
复制体是否能 复制到那种程度也未可知
We don't have enough information.
情报依旧不足
Edel, what do you think that is?
艾蒂露 你怎么看那个东西？
Who knows?
谁知道呢？
But there is no doubt that it is just as powerful
它的实力肯定跟一级魔法使的赞泽
as Sense, the first-class mage.
一样强 这点无庸置疑
We can't conceal our mana and hide here forever.
抑制魔力躲在这里也是有极限的
We'll have to defeat it.
必须打倒它才行
You think you can defeat it, Blei?
你认为自己能打倒它吗 布莱？
I know I'm out of the question,
我很清楚我自己是办不到的
but even you and Dünste can barely fight inside this dungeon.
但是就连你跟托斯特 也无法在这个迷宫中正面迎战
Modern magic isn't meant to be
当代魔法天生就不是
used to fight in dungeons to begin with.
用来在迷宫当中战斗用的
That's because most dungeons
因为大多数迷宫
were already done being raided during the Demon King's era.
在讨伐魔王的时代就已经被攻略完了
And we focus too much of our resources on powerful defensive magic.
然后又把过多的资源 投入在强力的防御魔法上
We've begun to rely more on natural elements for offensive magic.
攻击魔法就更加依赖大自然的物质
Because rather than creating something out of nothing,
比起无中生有
it takes up less mana to manipulate or transform
操纵或转变身边既有的物质
elements that are already accessible around us.
所耗费的魔力会更少
And in that sense, that thing is very efficient.
而就这一点来说 它可是非常厉害的
Its hair is covered in multiple layers of magic.
它的头发覆盖了层层魔法
It's safe to assume that it has numerous ways
我们大可假设在这座迷宫里
of fighting even inside this dungeon.
它有无数种的战斗方式
In my opinion, we can't win against that thing.
依我之见 我们是打不过它的
Magic is all about visualization.
所谓的魔法即是想象的世界
The fact that it can freely transform and manipulate
它能自由变化操控
each strand of hair, which is impossible to even count,
难以计数的每根发丝 这件事本身
means its ability to visualize is beyond any normal human being.
就意味着它具现化的能力 已经超越任何正常的人类了
That in itself makes it a far superior mage than us.
它本身就是远胜过我们的魔法使
Honestly, it's a miracle that we were able to evade it this far.
老实说 我们 能逃到这里已经是奇迹了
We did our best.
真的已经很拚了
First of all, we aren't even fighters.
话说回来 我们甚至不是战斗派
It's time to call it quits.
是时候该收手了
To be honest, I'm scared and want to go home.
坦白说 我很害怕 都想回家了
Edel,
艾蒂露
your voice won't reach it?
你的声音无法传达给它吗？
I may be from a clan which makes a living off of hypnosis magic,
我们一族确实是以精神操作魔法为职
but there is no way
但是要击败那个东西
I can meet the requirements to use high-level orders against that thing.
我根本无法满足 使用高阶命令所需的条件
At best, I'd only be able
最好的情况下也只能
to make it kneel and create a window of opportunity.
让它跪下来 制造出一点破绽
Even to do that, I'd have to look into its eyes and talk to it.
但是要做到这点 我就必须直视它的双眼说话
So it's not impossible?
所以也不是不可能 对吧？
Only if it has a mind.
只要它有心智的话就行
How much time do we need to buy?
我们要争取多少时间？
Fifteen seconds.
十五秒
You probably can't buy any more than that.
说起来那已经是你们的极限了
What do you mean?
什么意思啊？
You will find out soon.
你马上就会知道了
Surround us with defensive magic.
马上张开全面防御魔法
What?
什么？
In modern magic battles,
在现代魔法的战斗中
there are two ways to break through defensive magic.
要攻破防御魔法有两种办法
Either shatter it using sheer mass
不是用压倒性的质量
or slip past it using technique.
就是用实力强行攻破
Those with many tricks up their sleeve usually use the latter.
通常实力超群的人都会采用后者
How surprising…
真令人惊讶
Who knew it would use both methods.
没想到它两招都用上了
It's as powerful as a giant!
简直跟巨岩一样！
I thought a complete barrier of
我本以为全面防御魔法
defensive magic would last a maximum of 15 seconds.
至少能撑上十五秒
But who knew it would give out even sooner.
没想到比这个时间更短
But now we've made eye contact.
既然现在四目相对了
The more skilled a mage gets, the more they look at their opponent.
越优秀的魔法使就更能直视对手
Kneel!
跪下！
I see…
原来如此…
Now I understand.
现在我明白了
It doesn't have a mind.
它并没有心智
It's just imitating the workings of a mind very precisely.
只是单纯很精确地模仿了心智活动
There is no way for us to win against it.
我们是不可能打倒它的
We have no choice but to rely on others.
没办法了 只能靠别人了
Run with all your might and find those who can fight.
全力逃到能够战斗的考生那边吧
Like I said, it's time to call it quits and go home.
我之前也说了 是时候该收手回家了
I don't want to feel any more pain.
这实在痛得我受不了了
How handy.
还真是方便
You're even going to protect me from harm?
甚至还能保护我不受到伤害呢
We should run too.
我们也逃吧
At this rate, will anyone be able to reach the innermost depth unharmed?
照这样下去的话 有谁能毫发无伤地抵达最深处？
Didn't I call it?
我说过了吧？
She never intended to let anyone pass the exam in the first place.
打从一开始 她就没打算让任何人通过考试
Since we have such little information,
情报实在太少了
we should prepare just in case it doesn't have a mind.
最好以它没有心智的状况来做准备
In that case, we'll have to use sheer force.
这样一来就只能用蛮力硬攻了
Is that possible?
行得通吗？
I don't know.
不知道耶
Jeez…
真是的…
I can't even tell what they're thinking.
根本看不出它们在想什么
But just as I thought, we work pretty well together.
不过正如我所想的 我们的默契不错
If it's a simple head-to-head battle of mana,
如果只是纯粹以魔力决胜负的话
Ehre can overpower Scharf and I.
艾露的本事凌驾于夏鲁夫和我之上
However,
但是呢
I know how to win.
我很清楚怎么做能赢
No matter who I'm against
不论对手是谁
or what the circumstances are.
也不管是什么情况
By sheer force, huh?
靠蛮力吗？
Um, in that case…
那个 如果是这样的话…
I might be able to kill Mistress Frieren.
我说不定能杀掉芙莉莲大人
-Yeah? -Yes.
-是吗？ -是的
Well then,
这样的话
let's draft up a plan.
来制定作战计划吧
-It's coming together. -Let's draft up a plan.
-一起过来了 -制定作战计划吧
-So you had information. -Shall I help?
-你有情报 -该帮忙吗？
I think you should apologize.
还是道个歉比较妥当吧
-It has no weakness. -How unpleasant.
-没有弱点 -真是令人不悦
You look like you're having fun.
看起来很开心呢
"A Fatal Vulnerability."
《致命破绽》
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻译：洪贞韵